Laura Wall



lauramwall@outlook.com



740-466-2564



linkedin.com/in/lauramwall



www.laura.ga

Summary

Passionate and industry-experienced developer with a desire to learn new technologies and collaborate with successful cross-functional teams. Develops ADA compliant, responsive, and user-friendly code and authors Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) components on the University of Phoenix website in a fast-paced Agile environment. Previously developed and thoroughly tested marketing email campaign templates and HTML5 digital banner advertisements.

Skills

Web Development • Adobe Experience Manager • Responsive Web Design • Agile Methodologies • Jira • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • ¡Query • JavaScript • Content Management Systems (CMS)

Experience



Front End Developer - Phoenix.edu (Remote)

University of Phoenix

Oct 2019 - Present (Over 2 years)

- Builds clean, accurate HTML components and pages, coded for responsive design.
- Develops website components and user interfaces, building reusable code and templates and libraries for on-going use.
- Optimizes pages to meet site speed and accessibility requirements.
- · Incorporates ADA compliance, SEO, and site optimization best practices as needed.
- Collaborates closely with cross-functional teams to ensure output ready files meet final production requirements; troubleshoots issues, including technology and coding issues as necessary.



Senior Front End Developer – Marketing (In-Person/Remote)

University of Phoenix

Dec 2018 - Oct 2019 (11 months)

- Developed new user-facing features and/or modify existing features to increase functionality.
- Developed static digital banners of multiple sizes in Photoshop and optimized final files to meet size requirements.
- Developed clean, accurate HTML emails and coded to responsive design; troubleshooted and corrected complex HTML coding issues.
- Maintained and adhered to University brand standards in all production.
- Produced consistent presentation across all browser platforms by effectively manipulating text and graphics.

Education



Associate of Applied Science, Digital Media Design Technology – Web Design Central Ohio Technical College

2015 - 2017